NEW YORK STATE CONFERENCE OF LOCAL MENTAL HYGIENE DIRECTORS RECORDS (APAP315) 1950-2009
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Managed Care and Special Needs Plans, 1991-2000; Undated; 6; 2.0 cu. ft.
  Managed care, in its most general form, refers to coordination of health services in such a way that quality care is provided, but costs are kept low. Many of the records in this series deal with Medicare issues, of which special needs plans (SNPs) are an important part since they focus effort on particular groups of people with very specific needs. Researchers will find a variety of records such as memos, letters, information packets, and meeting notes covering areas like Medicare financing, managed care in rural areas, strategic planning, technical assistance, and committee work.
  - Adult special needs plans- Financing and public accountability, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany County HMO conflicts, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albany Law Review- Special Needs Plans: Adapting Medicaid Managed Care for Persons with Serious Mental Illness or HIV/AIDs, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alcohol and substance abuse subcommittee meetings, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assisted Outpatient Treatment-Volume 1, Initial implementation Sections 1-9, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Assisted Outpatient Treatment-Volume 1, Initial implementation Sections 10-16, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Booklet: "Mental Health Special Needs Plans Request for Information", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget survey/local assistance matches, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Central New York Consortium- Alternative managed care program, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CHPS Consulting, Inc.- Correspondence, meetings, and notes, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conference managed care meeting, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Consolidated fiscal reform, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Contracting for Public Mental Health Services" special report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - County chargebacks- Forensic legislation, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - County responses to SNP requests for information, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - County role in Special Needs Plans selection, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Effective Public Management of Mental Health Care..…" Report and notes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Health care financing administration 1115 waiver and award information, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Historical Medicaid cost and utilization data book, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Impact of Managed Behavioral Health Services on County-Operated Programs", 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Integrated services and managed care in rural areas, papers and articles, 1997-1998; 2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - International symposium and training seminar on Medicaid Managed Care, SUNY Albany, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Involuntary Outpatient Treatment, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Managed care basic plan contracts, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Managed care committee, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Managed care committee, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Managed care committee, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Managed care committee meetings, 1997 June; 1997 September (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Managed care committee meetings, 1997 October-1998 October (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Managed care consultant services, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Managed care reporting language- financial issues, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Managed care review/Advisory review panel- recommendations, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Managed care working group, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Managed care working group, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Managed mental health care models- California, 1995; 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Managing care of Schizophrenia"- Four-year study, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Mandatory Managed Care: Changes in Medicaid Mental Health Services"- Office of Inspector General, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mathematica study: Care coordination and Medicaid managed care, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Medicaid Managed Care: Four States' Experiences with Mental Health Carveout Programs", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Medicaid managed care task force, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Medicaid managed care task force, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Medicaid managed care uniform standards, 1992; 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Medicaid managed special care, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Medicaid waiver- Alcohol and Substance Abuse Subcommittee, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Medicaid waiver workgroup, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Memorandums- Managed care priorities, 1996; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mental health liaison group, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mental Health Weekly, Vol. 10 #25, 2000 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - New York City managed care issues, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "New York State HMOs and their role in Medicaid Managed Care", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - NYSCLMHD- Conference's role in managed care, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Office of Alcoholism and Substance Abuse Services- Evaluation and monitoring plan demos, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Other states' health care models- North Carolina and Oregon, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Overcoming Barriers to Effective Use of Behavioral Health Care Data: Opportunities for State and Local Collaboration", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "Parity in Financing Mental Health Services: Managed Care Effects on Cost, Access, and Quality", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Planning documents- Office of Mental Health, Westchester County, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Preparing for Managed Care Challenges" forum packet, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Proposal for the Development and Implementation of a Statewide Managed Care Action Plan, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Proposal to Establish Uniform Standards for Mental Health Managed Care Referral and Billing Processes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Report on Rate Methodology Underlying New York City SNP Requests for Proposals, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Request for Information responses- Special needs plans, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Revised Medicaid waiver, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Rochester Medicare Demonstration Project, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Senate- Assembly: Act to amend mental hygiene law, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Special needs plans legislation, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Special needs plans- Powerpoint overview, 1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Special needs plans regional forum, Batavia, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Specs- Consultant managed care action plan, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - State behavioral health headlines, Vol. I #27 (SAMHSA managed care), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - State of New York Office of the Comptroller- Audit of state mental health services and response of agency officials, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Steering committee conference calls- Medicaid managed care, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Strategic planning for managed care/CHPS Consulting, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
  - Survey results of technical assistance needs for implementing managed care within communities, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Technical assistance- Survey and finance issues, 1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Subject Files, 1985-2008; Undated; 7; 5.4 cu. ft.
  The subject files house documents of long-term value that do not belong to the Conference’s other record series. There are correspondence and memo files of specific members of the group, such as Peter Freed (counsel) and Gerry Landsberg (New York University), background on shared staff issues, and information on partnerships with the New York State divisions of alcohol abuse and chemical dependency as well as state housing committees. Researchers will also find documents pertaining to consolidation of services and positions over the years, particularly in the 1990s. Additionally, there are manuals, booklets, and conference materials about disaster preparedness in the mental health profession. Most of the collection’s photographs are also located in this series, with the exception of the Commission on the 21st Century images which are in Series #5.
  - 2002 Regulatory review workgroup, 1994; 2001; 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2002 Regulatory review workgroup (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2002 Regulatory review workgroup, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adult homes- Issues and recommendations, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adult homes workgroup, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual report: Serving the mental health needs of young offenders, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Assessing the nature and prevalence of mentally ill in Suffolk County's criminal justice system", 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "At the Crossroads" Reinvestment/realignment report and supplementary materials, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bond, Schoeneck, and King, Attorneys at Law, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Mental Health, Mental Retardation, and Developmental Disabilities: "Broken Promises, Broken Lives" status report, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Committees and task forces, 1996; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Community service boards: Training, 1990-1992; 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community services block grant- Management plan, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Comprehensive Psychiatric Emergency Programs, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Conference goals and missions- overview packet, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Consolidated fiscal reform (CFR), 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Consultant contract: Tremblay Associates, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Courage to Change: A Guide for Communities to Create Integrated Services", 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Cost of Addictive and Mental Disorders and Effectiveness of Treatment", Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - County charges- Medicaid, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - County Programs, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - County reinvestment, 1993; 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - County reinvestment surveys, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Department of Health licensing verification edits, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Director of Community Services and Commissioner of Social Services- Serving a dual role, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Director of Community Services credentials and qualifications, 1989; 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Director of Community Services credentials and qualifications, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Directory: New York State Conference of Local Mental Hygiene Directors, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Disaster planning: All-hazards planning worksheet, 2003 November (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Disaster planning:Communicating in a Crisis- Risk Communication Guidelines for Public Officials, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Disaster planning: Data collection toolkit, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Disaster planning: Department of Health and Human Services, 2002 June (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Disaster planning:Developing Culture Competence, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Disaster planning:Disaster Mental Health Response Handbook, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Disaster planning:Disaster Mental Health Services, 1997 September (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Disaster planning:Disaster Mental Health Services I- Participant's Workbook, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Disaster planning: Draft-"Mental Health and Mass Violence" best practices report, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Disaster planning: Federation of Families for Children's Mental Health- "Claiming Children", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Disaster planning: Field manual for mental health and human service workers in major disasters, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Disaster planning: Grief counseling resource guide, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Disaster planning: Hurricane Katrina reception plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Disaster planning: "Impact of September 11, 2001- Events on substance use and mental health in the New York area", 2003 January (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Disaster planning: "Lessons from Disaster- A Conference and Conversation", SUNY New Paltz, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Disaster planning:Mental Health All-Hazards Disaster Planning Guidance, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Disaster planning:Mental Health Emergency Response Plan, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Disaster planning:Mental Health Interventions following Major Disasters- A Guide, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Disaster planning: NYS Office of Mental Health Incident Command System- Powerpoint slides, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Disaster planning: NYSPA notebook, 2001 November-December (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Disaster planning:Preparing for the Psychological Consequences of Terrorism, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Disaster planning: Project Liberty training presentations (Powerpoint slides), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Disaster planning:Psychological Issues for Children and Adolescents in Disasters, 2004 February (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Disaster planning: State mental health authorities' response to terrorism, 2004 February (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Disaster planning: Training manuals, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Disaster planning:When a Person with Mental Illness is Arrested- How to Help, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Disproportionate Share Hospitals (DSH) and Medicaid, 1997; 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse: Bulletin, Vol. II #7, 1991 October (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse: Correspondence, newsletters, and press releases, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Division of Alcohol Abuse: Director's office, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse: Family support communities, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Division of Substance Abuse services: Consolidation with Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Division of Substance Abuse Services: Correspondence and accompanying materials, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Division of Substance Abuse Services: Director's office, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Division of Substance Abuse Services: "Executive budget recommendations", 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Division of Substance Abuse Services: Merger with Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Division of Substance Abuse Services: Merger with Division of Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse Services- legislation, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Division of Substance Abuse Services: Rate-setting proposal, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dornan, Douglas- Retirement speech, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Double Jeopardy: Persons with mental illnesses in the criminal justice system", 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dungan, Stephen- Conference chair materials, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Families Together" newsletter, Fall issue, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fingerprinting- Chapter 575 of Laws of 2004, information meeting, 2004-2006 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Forensic Mental Health Conference, Buffalo, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Forensic Mental Health Conference, Kingston, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Forensic Mental Health Conference, Lake Placid, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Forensic Mental Health Regional Conference, Long Island, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Forensic site visits, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Forensics: Criminal justice and prison issues, 1994; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Forensics: General information, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Forensics: Risk assessment training, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Freed, Peter- Correspondence, 1989; 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Freed, Peter- Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Freed, Peter- Counsel on mental health initiatives, 1991; 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Governor's program bill #206, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Gowanda consolidation plan testimony, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Healthcare: 32-day limit on Medicaid, 1985; 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Healthcare: 32-day limit on Medicaid, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Healthcare Recruitment and Retention Act, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Innovation group- background packet, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Jail diversion: Knowledge development and application program, Undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Jail diversion survey, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Jail/mental health symposium surveys, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Landsberg, Gerry: Intensive case management, 1989; 1991-1992; 1998 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Long-term care in New York State- task force report from governor's office, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Mandate relief workgroup, 1994; 1950-2008 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - MDI Associates, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Medicaid community support programs- notes, reports, letters, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Medicaid community support programs- notes, reports, letters, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Medicaid community support programs- rate calculation sheets, 1997 August (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Medicaid community support programs- rate calculation sheets, 1997 December (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Medicaid community support programs- regulations/ conference comments, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Medicaid managed care committees, 1996; Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Medicaid- state takeover, 1989; 1991; 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mental health care in prison- background materials, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mental health court legislation, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - National Association of County Behavioral Health Directors, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - National GAINS Center, 1996-1999; Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - National GAINS Center and Rensselaer County Department of Mental Health, 2000; Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - New York State Division of Housing and community housing renewal, 1990; 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - New York State Division of Housing and community housing renewal, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - New York State Division of Housing and community housing renewal, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - New York State comprehensive housing affordability strategy, 1992; 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - New York State Comptroller's office- Edward V. Regan, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - New York State Comptroller's office- Edward V. Regan, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - New York State Office of Advocate for the Disabled, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - New York State Sheriffs' Association Institute- Jail administrator's training conference, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - NYS Division of Probation and Correctional Alternatives annual report, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - NYS Office of Mental Health: Leaders of the Mental Health Response Training Program, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - OASAS booklet: "Collaboration- OASAS and the Criminal Justice System", 2001 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - OASAS booklet: "Substance Abuse Treatment for Persons in the Criminal Justice System", 2001 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Office of Mental Health Assisted Outpatient Treatment implementation plan, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Office of Mental Health Blueprint- 21st Century health care, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Office of Mental Health: Flexible Funding Plan and Federal Single Audit Act, 1996; 1997 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Office of Mental Health: High needs regulations, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Office of Mental Health: Involuntary commitment, 1991; 1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Olmstead Decision, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Pataki transition team, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photo directories from NYSCLMHD website, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, mainly unidentified- Includes NYSCLHMD 10th anniversary and photo negatives, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Planning and Implementing Effective Mental Health Services in Jail", Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Policy Research Associates: Organizational overview and recent projects, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Press clippings, 1994-1995; 2004; Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Press contacts, 1990; 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Prisons and Jails: Hospitals of Last Resort", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Progress report on New York State's Public Mental Health System"/Shared caseload workgroups, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Regional forensics conferences, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Reinvestment- Census reduction, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Reinvestment extender, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Reinvestment guidelines and reports, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Reinvestment reporting- Office of Mental Health, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Report of the Adult Care Facilities Workgroup to Commissioner Antonia Novello, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Risk management workshop, New York City, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation: "Building Healthy Systems for People with Chronic Illness", 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Shared staff: Aggregate statewide costs, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Shared staff: Assisted Outpatient Treatment budget requests by county, A-N, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Shared staff: Assisted Outpatient Treatment budget requests by county, O-Y, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Shared staff: Background and legislation, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Shared staff: Data summary charts, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Shared staff: Estimated numbers of clients affected by loss of staff, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Shared staff: Impact by county, A-E, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Shared staff: Impact by county, G-W, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Shared staff: Impact data, 1999-2000; 2002 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Shared staff: Information packet, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Shared staff: Letters of support, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Shared staff: Letters, memos, and accompanying materials, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Shared staff: Letters to legislature, Office of Mental Health, DOB, and governor, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Shared staff: Long-term recommendations, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Shared staff: Planning, 2000; 2003 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Shared staff: Requests to NY State Legislature for restoration of shared staff funding, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Shared staff: Responses from legislature to Steve Dungan, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Shared staff: Responses to potential personnel reductions, 1995; 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Shared staff: Strategies to divert cuts, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Shared staff: Survey, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Shared staff: Survey- transitional, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Shared staff: Transition plan, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Shared staff: Workgroup conference calls, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - State comptroller's report on mental health planning services, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Statewide comprehensive plan for mental health services, 2002-2006, ca. 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Technical Assistance Project success story, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Technical Assistance Project- Timetables, budget, agendas, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF), Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Transitions" training manual and handouts, 1999; Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Transitions" training transparencies, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - T-shirt commemorating 30th anniversary of NYSCLMHD, 2006 (Oversized 1)
  - Welfare-to-Work Conference, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Newsletters, 1980-2008; Undated; 8; 0.6 cu. ft.
  The Conference began publishing its own newsletter in the early days of its existence, but most of the issues from the 1980s and 1990s are not included in this collection. Researchers will find a consistent run from 1979 through 1981, a few issues from 1993, 1994, and the late 1990s, then another consistent run from 2000 through 2008. There are also several issues of a newsletter published specially by the Conference chair.
  - January-December, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mental Hygiene News, winter, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mental Hygiene News, winter, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Conference Update, spring edition, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Conference Update, special anniversary issue, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)